

RODJEL ROWEL CUEBILLAS

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Phone: 0908-872-4991

E-mail: cuebillasrodjelrowel@gmail.com

PROFILE

A nurse turned into a passionate software engineer with almost 3 years of experience in full-stack Java development. Top 1 out of 16 IT and engineering graduates in Java bootcamp. Solved a critical bug for 3 days that took dev leads several weeks but was still left unsolved. Identified 4 critical bugs after QA testers finished testing the application. Proficient with Java, Spring, Front-End frameworks, SQL, JMeter, Salesforce and RPA. Communication, Collaboration, Critical Thinking, and Project Management skills were further enhanced by 4 years of experience in customer service. Interested in Algorithms, Clean Code, Al and Machine Learning.

EXPERIENCE

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Pointwest Innovations Corporation (April, 2016 - present)

- Writing well-designed, testable, efficient code.
- Performing code review and applying knowledge on latest Java coding best practices.
- Supporting continuous improvement by investigating alternatives and technologies and presenting these for architectural review

MAS HRB OPEN ENROLLMENT SENIOR ANALYST

ADP Philippines, Inc. (July, 2014 - March, 2016)

Assisted several clients in different phases/milestones of Open Enrollment

CUSTOMER SERVICE REPRESENTATIVE, SR.

UnitedHealth Group (February, 2013 - June, 2014)

• Assisted healthcare providers with claims and denials

CARE MANAGEMENT ANALYST

Accenture (May, 2011 - December, 2012)

- Assisted healthcare providers with prior authorizations for procedures
- Worked with the IT team to handle process improvements(macros and visual basic in excel)

SKILLS

- Java, Spring
- Front-End Frameworks(Angular, React, Vue, Bootstrap)
- MySQL, MSSQL
- · CentOS, Linux
- Jmeter, Salesforce, RPA

EDUCATION

BS NURSING

Bicol University (2005 - 2009)